hi I'm Bonnie and I'm recording this
from all the lore the home of all the
large soul when Sugata Mitra first
coined the term soul he meant it a
self-organized learning environment and
all the Lord we like to think of it as
self-organizing learning experience
because that's what we're offering we're
offering young adults an opportunity to
come together work collectively work on
an individual project take advantage of
this beautiful environment that were
located in a western part of Connecticut
and learn how to self-organize their own
learning experiences to make them rich
and profound and purposeful now ever
since we launched our website last month
than having a lot of inquiries from all
over the world people really wanting to
know a little bit more about me about
what my vision is and what my
educational philosophy is so this video
is an attempt to connect on that level
and kind of give you a sense of how all
the lower soul came into being and what
we would really hope we can make of it
in 2006 I went to a conference where the
keynote speaker was stephen scott glenn
means a very dynamic speaker and he told
the story about einstein and Einstein's
predictions and visions for the future
pretty much in the time period we're
living now and Einstein said that in the
future machines would take care of a lot
of the knowledge base work that we do
now or we had done in the past just like
machines take care of a lot of
repetitive physical work for us Einstein
saw that knowledge itself would become
in the future like data was for him then
there was organizing storing and
retrieving data was the work of
computers and today what we're seeing
with
smarter and smarter computers and the
development of artificial intelligence
and the Semantic Web and crowdsourcing
and having computers learned from
collective engagement with people what
we're seeing is that machines are being
able to be very competent in organizing
storing and retrieving knowledge so in
the past they exclusively machines
exclusively worked with data and it
required people to use the data to make
into knowledge systems but today we're
finding as I as an Isaan Einstein
predicted that machines are getting
increasingly better than us at organized
storing and retrieving knowledge so this
has huge implications it has huge
implications for students entering
college at this time in terms of what
are going we are going to be the careers
available to them so the implication
that means for me today is that our
responsibilities as adults and educators
is to support the development of skills
in young adults that machines can't do
that are our responsibility is to
cultivate new capacities perhaps in many
instances in human development that are
beyond the range of technology at this
moment and then everything moves along
so that was one of the first really
important signposts for me back in 2006
in 2006 in that same keynote speech
Stephen Glen said that Einstein was very
fascinated with the rate of knowledge
throughout you know recent history in
that in the past for example my parents
parents knowledge doubled so slowly that
the only responsibility parents and
cheers had was to reproduce the
knowledge that they have been given and
make sure that that was adequately
passed on to their children fast forward
to when I was in college it seemed to me
that knowledge was doubling so rapidly
that by the time you got into college
you are faced with research agendas into
the unknown and recently I heard a man
speak about the kind of pickle that
children are in in terms of the fact
that when there by the time they receive
all the knowledge in a certain
discipline then that knowledge is
already obsolete and so that they're
faced with skills that they haven't
learned so if you're graduating from
college and you have all this knowledge
and even in many of the sciences you
have to go on to post doc and docx drill
so you might spend 30 years in an
institution where you're just receiving
knowledge but then by the time you've
accumulated all that knowledge then the
research has really advanced way forward
and so it's really hard for children at
that stage or adults at that stage to
make the transition to where they're
doing research where they're asking
questions of the unknown so that was a
second sign post in that keynote speech
that really got me to thinking and then
the third thing that's Stephen a Glenn
said in the keynote speech was that
again the rate of knowledge is
developing so fast that now knowledge
doubles faster than a generation I read
something the other day that knowledge
doubles in less than a year so if we
really take that to heart what what that
is saying is that by the time children
are born and into our responsibility
then we don't know what to teach them we
we are way behind the curve ball here
and so knowledge is doubling so fast
that we are in the
situation where we are not only teaching
our children skills to face an unknown
future but in unknowable future and that
had a really big impact on me so we have
these three aspects number one that
machines are going to be able to
organize store and retrieve knowledge
better than humans so that humans have
to develop capacities way ahead of the
technological curve number two that
research is requires so much received
knowledge that by the time you actually
internalize all those knowledge you
number one are way behind the curve and
number two don't have the skills for
doing action inquiry into the unknown
for innovation in an invention in number
three that educators and teachers and
parents are in the situation of having
to design an educational system and
having to support their children in the
capacity of creating capabilities for
them to fix not only an unknown future
but an unknowable future and I think we
really really really need to take that
to heart that we need to stop thinking
that our children need received
knowledge not only do they not need it
but that can be handled by machines but
that it is doing them a disservice and
the third point is that we need to take
on the responsibility of identifying
what are the capabilities that our
children need to face an unknown and
unknowable future to talk to them like
that to say we don't know what your
future is going to be like what we can
do is support your own growth in the
capacities that you will need to face an
unknown
future recently I've been thinking about
how special and innovative and creative
young adults are and I've been going
around the country doing workshops on
inside practice and inevitably when
there are intergenerational people in my
workshop it is very clear that young
adults would say 35 and younger have a
completely different mindset a
completely different understanding of
how of change in the world how change
happens the kinds of process
methodologies that are important to them
and I'm not sure that this is schooled
in them I think that this is a
evolutionary leap and I'll tell you why
my research has shown me that one of the
most significant changes or significant
situations we are dealing with today in
terms of this educational and
intergenerational aspect of our
situation is that children are now born
into a world that's so technologically
advanced that this makes a huge
difference in how they come to think
about reality so for example I grew up
before I was grew up in a school system
before there were personal computers
I've seen the development of personal
computers over time I've learned from
the beginning in both in business and in
school and I've seen how how the web has
changed over the last ten years so for
me this has a the internet is a kind of
a relative or a contingent aspect of
reality I remember what it was like
before but for children who are now
thrown into the world where a digital
world
the world of digital technology in the
internet in collective intelligence this
is not a contingent aspect of their
world this is the real world and so that
creates a situation where the world
feedbacks to them in a much different
way than it did to us and this creates
actual evolutionary leap in the
cognitive architecture of our children
so this is another situation that I
think as educators we have to take to
heart and we have to design education
now for children that in a certain sense
in the context that they're born
actually smarter than us that they have
insights into this world that we do not
have simply by the fact of this
thoroughness this thrown into a world
that is different than the world we
experienced as children so I like to
tell children that they are penguins and
it's a little story I wanted to share
with you there's this great documentary
called march of the penguins you
probably have seen it and most people
remember the part of the story where the
Penguins take the Long March and deep
into the Antarctic and they pair up and
the female lays an egg and then the egg
gets passed to the male and females make
the long march to the sea to feed and
then in this in the early spring the
females make the long march back the
chicks are born they exchange they find
their mate they exchange their chick and
the males make the long march to the sea
because they're starving so most people
remember the story for the profound
challenges of parenthood and the
responsibilities so but for me the most
surprising and the thing that stuck with
me the most was at the point then that
the the mothers are now feeding their
chicks just from the storage
of food that they had been eating when
they were in the sea and the chicks are
going in the and the mothers are
starting to start to death so then at a
certain point they make the long march
to the sea back to feed and the
interesting things is the chicks wait
they're all the same generation they're
all cousins and they wait and they wait
and they wait and what they don't know
is no one's coming back for them so this
is extraordinary because in the movie
you see they're all the chicks are
getting hungry and restless and they all
kind of like congregate and move around
nervously and then all of a sudden
there's this kind of like
self-organizing scene happening and the
natural born leader start to get
together in little groups and then it's
like a congress and they they kind of
like talk to each other and it really
looks like they're making decisions and
the whole colony kind of self organizes
as if they're the central meaning of
this generation and then that at some
point some inner knowing kicks in and
then that little Congress starts to lead
and they make the march to the sea and
at each point where there's challenges
there may be fishers or water rolls or
some dangers then that little Congress
gets together like trying kind of
collectively making a decision and they
move forward until they get to the seat
and this is a generation that has never
made them large it's all from an inner
knowing led by natural born leaders they
get to the sea they've never seen the
sea before and in the last scenes of the
movie the same kind of initiation
happens where the Congress starts to
look into the water and they get to like
cackling to each other and then finally
someone dies and then the next one the
next one and
that becomes a generation that lives
together so I like to think of the
generations that are born today as
penguins because of this rapid advance
of both technology and knowledge
building in a sense they're born left
alone they are born to self-organize
they are in a situation where they have
to find each other find their natural
born leaders self-organized and move
into an unknown future from some kind of
deep inter knowing that we as educators
teachers and parents need to learn how
to cultivate and for them and how to
support the cultivation of that so that
is what for me over the last 12 years or
so has been a progression progressive
research inquiry and understanding into
what what do we need to be as educators
adults and parents to really support
children into transforming their own
future and I think this is an essential
responsibility that we have at this time
in history
you